Preliminary Guide to the Thomas Timings Holme Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Thomas Timings Holme papers
1936-1962
MS 1130
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
9
The papers consist of correspondence, typescripts, reports, and materials connected with Thomas Timings Holme's teaching career at Lehigh University and Yale University. The Lehigh material includes correspondence and course materials while the Yale material consists of correspondence, course materials, and data on budgets and inspection trips.
Holme, Thomas Timings, 1913-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Thomas T. Holme, 1961.
Conditions Governing Access
Student grades iin boxes 4 and 5 are restricted until 2037.
Biographical / Historical
Thomas Timings Holme received his B.S. degree from Lehigh University in 1935, his M.S. in 1940, and his I.E. (profl.) in 1948. He was a professor of mechanical engineering at Lehigh from 1937-1950, and head of the engineering department from 1949-1950. Holme was a professor of engineering at Yale from 1950-1973, and chairman of the department from 1954-1963. Holme was a consultant to the U.S. Army and to various corporations.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, typescripts, reports, and materials connected with Thomas Timings Holme's teaching career at Lehigh University and Yale University. The Lehigh material includes correspondence and course materials while the Yale material consists of correspondence, course materials, and data on budgets and inspection trips.
Engineering; Industrial engineering -- Study and teaching; Engineers; Holme, Thomas Timings, 1913-; Lehigh University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Faculty
- Inventory
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1936-1949 (Box 1)
    - A-W, 1957-1962 (Box 1)
    - With students and student applicants, 1957-1962 (Box 1)
    - Concerning speaking engagements, 1948-1955 (Box 1)
  - Manuscripts and typescripts, 1938-1941 (Box 1)
  - Organizations and companies [alphabetical correspondence], 1948-1961 (Box 2)
  - Lehigh University [correspondence, course materials, correspondence concerning recommendations] (Box 2)
  - Yale University correspondence (Box 2)
    - Air Force-Budget, 1951-1962 (Box 3)
    - Budget-Courses, 1951-1962 (Box 4)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Course folders including hand-outs, class lists and list of grades are restricted until January 1, 2037 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - Courses-Engineering, 1951-1962 (Box 5)
    - Faculty-Industrial administration, 1951-1962 (Box 6)
    - Industrial administration-Inspection trips, 1951-1962 (Box 7)
    - Inspection trips-Y, and miscellaneous, 1951-1962 (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous manuscripts and reports, mostly relating to Springfield Armory, 1945-1957 (Box 9)